(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-04T22:16:48.311197",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
惰慢姫
[Lazy Princess]
バズスリップ 好きなステップで踊り出すビート
Buzz slip, dancing to the beat with my favorite steps
宵に輝くネオンの下で光る
Shining under the neon lights that glow in the evening
私 可愛い可愛い召使い達 あの子はどこに？
My cute, cute servants, where is that child?
うだうだ ゴロゴロ ガラガラ にゃんにゃん 何もし損ねた
Idling, rolling around, clattering, meowing, I failed to do anything
甘い甘い チョコが食べたい
I want to eat sweet, sweet chocolate
熱い熱い ラテが飲みたい
I want to drink hot, hot latte
サクサクのパン 食べたいの
I want to eat crispy bread...
ダメ？
Is that a no?
とろとろのチーズ 食べたい
I want to eat melty cheese
ふかふかのベッドで寝たい
I want to sleep in a fluffy bed
うとうと おやすみなさい
Dozing off... Good night
すぴー
Snooze...
わがままらんらんらん
Selfish, ran-ran-ran
怒らないで 私可愛いそうでしょ
Don't be mad, I look so cute, right?
お願いギブギブミー 尽くして愛届けて
Please, give, give to me, serve me and send me love
何事も許される
Anything and everything is forgiven
だって私が一番可愛いんだから
Because I'm the absolute cutest, after all
スリッツ 香ばしい匂いで騒ぎ出すビート
Sweets, the beat goes wild with a sweet scent
宵月明かりの下で
Under the evening moonlight
誰をやーる？ ギロチン 銃殺 火あぶり 切腹 お好きなオプションで
Who should I do in? Guillotine, firing squad, burning at the stake, seppuku, choose your favorite option
誰も私には勝てない 偽りはいらない
No one can defeat me, I don't need falseness
苦い苦い キモが食べたい
I want to eat bitter, bitter liver
赤い赤い スープ飲みたい
I want to drink red, red soup
コクコク お肉食べたいの
I want to eat rich, flavorful meat
甘ーい！
So sweet!
甘い甘い それじゃ足りない
Sweet, sweet, that's still not enough
油断の隙 また見せて
Show me a slip in your guard again
ラランラランラランララン
La-ran, la-ran, la-ran, la-ran
ほら まだまだ足りないわ
Look, it's still not enough
わがままな私のこと愛してくれる誰かを待っているの
I'm waiting for someone who will love me for being so selfish
孤独じゃないって言いにひとり目を覚まして
Waking up alone just to say I'm not lonely
洋服もまだ迷ってる
I'm still undecided on what to wear...
だって私が
Because I'm...
ね？ わがままなランタン
Right? A selfish lantern.
誰も怖がらないって
They say no one is afraid of me...
私可愛いでしょう？
Aren't I cute?
お願い ギブギブミー 全て与え続けて
Please, give, give me, keep giving me everything...
何もかも許される
Everything is forgiven...
やっぱ私が一番可愛いんだから
After all, I'm the cutest of all.
Myth or treat
Trick or treat
キミの推しはクローゼットの中でドッキリを仕掛けた
Your fave set up a prank inside the closet
TRICK OR TREAT ほら もうキャンディーはない
TRICK OR TREAT, look, there's no more candy
お腹がいっぱい？ じゃあ、チェーンソーの出番かな？
Full already? Then is it time for the chainsaw?
みんなが取り憑かれた その仮説を確かめよう 解剖しよう
Everyone's possessed—let me test that hypothesis and dissect it
踊れ 隠れないで 泣き虫
Dance, don't hide, crybaby
幻獣のない HALLOWEEN は面白くない Haha
Halloween without mythical beasts is no fun, haha
みんなが照れている
Everyone is glowing
かわいい
How cute
熱くなった血をくれるでしょう？
You'll give us your heated blood, right?
Myth or treat
あぁ、呪いの配信
Ah, a cursed stream
びびって叫んじゃえ！
Get scared and scream!
見せるよ今夜だけ まだ見ぬ恐ろしい顔を
Only tonight, we'll show you an unseen, terrifying face
なんてガチ恋 NIGHT
What a true-love NIGHT
魔女たちの出番だ
It's time for the witches to take the stage
もう逃げられないよ 捧げて君の魂を
You can't run away anymore, surrender your soul
踊りだせ TONIGHT
Start dancing TONIGHT
見て恐ろしい SIGHT
Look at this terrifying SIGHT
腹ペコだ、食べたいねぇ、ちょうだい？
Starving, want to eat, won't you give it to me?
恐怖でびびらせ 一緒に歌おう
Scared out of your wits, let me hear you sing along
「嫁」じゃなくて かぼちゃよ DING-DONG？
Not a "wife", it's a pumpkin, DING-DONG?
墓場で待ってる 覚悟できてる？
Waiting in the graveyard, are you prepared?
我らの歌で盛り上がるがいい！
Get hyped up with our song!
べー！ふふっ
Bleah! Hehe
おびえて叫べ！
Cower and scream!
MYTHが暴れる これぞ我らのスタイル
MYTH goes wild, this is our style
イエーイ！
Yay!
やったー！ 楽しかったー！
Yay! That was so much fun!
いやー、すごかった！ いい曲だったね！
Wow, that was amazing! What a great song!
ねー！ ほんとに！ 歌えてめっちゃ嬉しい！
Right?! Seriously! I'm so happy we got to sing it!
あー、早く私も3Dで踊りたいよー！
Ah, I want to dance in 3D soon too!
見たい！ オリジナルの3D早く見たい！
I want to see it! I want to see your 3D model soon!
いつになれるのー？
When will that be?
分かんなーい！
I don't know!
分かんないけど、楽しみにしててねー！
I don't know, but please look forward to it!
でもなんか、今日2Dだけど、そう、いい感じに後ろにさ！
But even though you're in 2D today, you're set up so nicely in the background!
ね！ 確かに！ 画面がすごい！
Right! Definitely! The screen looks amazing!
でかい！ でかいね！
It's huge! Huge!
そうだね！ すごい！
That's right! Amazing!
このMyth or Treatは元々ENのみんなで英語で歌った曲だったんだけど
Myth or Treat was originally sung in English by all of EN,
日本語でまさか歌えるなんて思ってなかったです！ 嬉しい！
but I never thought we'd get to sing it in Japanese! I'm so happy!
うん！ でもこの曲さ、聴いたときからめっちゃ大好きな曲だったから、嬉しいよー！
Yeah! I've loved this song ever since I first heard it, so I'm so glad!
日本語版すごい自然に聞こえて、すごく歌いやすくてすごかった！
The Japanese version sounded so natural and was so easy to sing! It was awesome!
ほんと？ 結構自分でね、「これやったら可愛いかな？」っていう風にちょっと直してみた！
Really? I actually adjusted the lyrics a bit myself, thinking "would this be cuter?"
おー！ すごい！ 自分で？
Oh! Wow! Yourself?
メル様のこの誕生日に歌うっていうのもね、なかなかじゃないですか！
And singing it on Mel-sama's birthday like this is pretty special, isn't it!
おー、嬉しい！ やっぱハロウィンだからさ、ぴったりだよね、この曲ね！
Oh, I'm so happy! Since it's Halloween, this song is perfect!
ね！ ハロウィン！
Right! Halloween!
いやもうメル様お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday, Mel-sama!
この後もいろいろあるんじゃないですか？
Don't you have a lot more planned after this?
あ、そうなんだよ！ まだ2曲目だからさ、まだまだ歌うんだけど...
Ah, that's right! This is only the second song, so I still have plenty left to sing...
え、なんか帰る感じ？
Huh? Are you guys leaving already?
いやー、今日はね、ハロウィンだから、また他のお友達にお菓子いっぱいもらいに行かないといけないんです〜
Well, today is Halloween, so we have to go get lots of candy from our other friends~
え？ちょっと待って！
Wait, hold on!
だってさ、魔界のチョコがさ、めちゃめちゃ言ってた、チョコお腹すいた〜
Because Choco from the Demon Realm was constantly complaining, "Choco is so hungry~"
あ〜分かる！お腹すいた〜！
Ah, I get it! I'm so hungry!
食べに行っちゃう？食べに行っちゃう？
Should we go eat? Should we go eat?
ちょっと待って！メルも行きたい！
Wait a second! Mel wants to go too!
ダメダメダメ！いっぱいあるー！
No, no, no! There's plenty to get!
待ってよー！
Wait up!
ねぇ、ズルい！ズルい！置いていかないで！待って！
Hey, that's not fair! Don't leave me behind! Wait!
あー！待ってよー！待ってー！
Ahhh! Wait for me! Wait!
頑張ってね〜！
Good luck out there~!
おい、ちょっとよ…「頑張ってね」って…
Hey, wait a minute... What do you mean, "Good luck"?
えー？本当に…もう寂しいじゃん！
Huh? Seriously... Now I'm all lonely!
あ、でも今日はね、かぷみんのみんながいるよね！
Ah, but today, all of you Kapumin are here with me, right?
よし！
Alright!
改めてみんな、こんかぷー！
Once again, Konkapu, everyone!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、夜空メルでーす！
I'm the genius vampire of the Demon Realm, Yozora Mel!
今日は最後まで楽しんでいってください！
Please enjoy yourselves until the very end today!
そしてそして、#夜空メル生誕2022 でいっぱいツイートしてね！
And also, please tweet a lot with #夜空メル生誕2022!
写真もバシャバシャ撮ってください！
Take tons of screenshots too!
後でメル、見に行くからな！
Mel will go check them out later!
約束だよ！
That's a promise!
この後もまだまだコラボとか、ソロ曲とか、たくさん続くので、
There are still plenty of collabs and solo songs coming up after this,
ぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでいってください！
so please be sure to enjoy until the very end!
よーし、それじゃあ！
Alright then!
この後も、一緒に楽しんでいくぞー！
Let's keep having fun for the rest of the show!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
戦場へ! 前線へ! そして死の淵まで!
To the battlefield! To the front lines! And to the brink of death!
命捨てたその覚悟を示せ!
Show the resolve of having cast your life away!
聴こえるだろう あの砲声が
You can hear it, can't you? That roar of artillery...
抵抗する蠢の音だ
It's the sound of squirming resistance!
踏み潰せ! 踏み潰せ!
Crush them underfoot! Trample them down!
諸君、我々の任務は何だ？
Gentlemen, what is our mission?
殲滅だ！
Annihilation!
一機残らずの殲滅だ！
Complete annihilation, down to the last unit!
為すべきことは唯一つ
There is only one thing left to do...
地獄を創れ！
Create a hell!
何故炎の中進んで行くのか
Why do we march into the flames?
弾丸の雨に打たれに行くのか
Why do we march into a hail of bullets?
笑止千万! 帝国の為だ!
Laughable! It is for the Empire!
戦場へ! 前線へ! そして死の淵まで!
To the battlefield! To the front lines! And to the brink of death!
命捨てた覚悟を示せよ!
Show the resolve of having cast your life away!
忠誠を! 従順を! そして其の魂を
Offer up your loyalty! Your obedience! And all your soul!
全て捧げ勝鬨を上げよ!
Sacrifice everything and raise a cry of victory!
さあ此処に築いてみせろ!
Now, build it here before us!
天に届く死体の山を!
A mountain of corpses reaching up to the heavens!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
どこに恐怖があると言うんだ
Where is this fear you speak of?
見ろ 血肉が花火の様だ
Look, the flesh and blood are like fireworks!
撒き散らす 撒き散らす 千の傷痕
Scattering, scattering thousands of scars!
忘れちゃいないさ
I haven't forgotten them...
炎の熱も
Not the heat of the flames,
零れた臓腑も
nor the spilled entrails,
最後の呻きも
nor the final groans,
濁った瞳も
nor the clouded eyes...
嗚呼、それこそを求めるのだ!
Ah, that is precisely what we seek!
安寧も平穏も妄して和解なんて
Peace and tranquility? Talking about reconciliation...
牙を捨てた飼い犬の所業
That is the work of a pet dog that lost its fangs!
絶望と動乱を掛けた狂気の沙汰は
Madness forged through despair and turmoil...
地獄よりも 楽園の様だ
Is far more like paradise than hell!
その四肢は踊る為に
Those four limbs exist to dance,
踊り狂う為有るのだ!
to dance in madness!
人間価値など無い
Humans have no value!
価値無き者同士の争いに
In a fight between worthless beings,
命の徒花を咲かせてみせろ!
make the empty flowers of life bloom!
法律も秩序でも
Laws or order,
狂った奴が創ってる
are created by madmen!
まさに笑劇
Truly a farce!
不条理だけの
Filled with nothing but absurdity,
起承転結
from beginning to end!
戦場へ! 前線へ! そして死の淵まで!
To the battlefield! To the front lines! And to the brink of death!
命捨てた覚悟を示せよ!
Show the resolve of having cast your life away!
忠誠を! 従順を! そして其の魂を
Offer up your loyalty! Your obedience! And all your soul!
全て捧げ勝鬨を上げよ!
Sacrifice everything and raise a cry of victory!
さあ此処に築いてみせろ!
Now, build it here before us!
天に届く死体の山に
On the mountain of corpses reaching up to the heavens,
こだまする憎しみさえ
even the echoing hatred,
かき消す爆発音!
is drowned out by the roar of explosions!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Cover! Down! Halt!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Cover! Down! Halt!
メル先輩、誕生日おめでとう！
Mel-senpai, happy birthday!
ラプラスちゃん、ありがとう！
Laplus-chan, thank you!
なかなかカッコよく決まったんじゃない？
Didn't that turn out pretty cool?
まあ、元々かっこいいすけどね。
Well, I was cool to begin with, though.
こんなにさ、ちっちゃいのにびっくりしたよ、メル。
Mel was so surprised at how tiny you are.
ちっちゃい？ ちっちゃいって何言ってるんですか、ほら！
Tiny? What do you mean tiny? Look!
これ見て！ 角、角、角！ ほらほら！
Look at these! Horns, horns, horns! Look, look!
ちょっと比べてみよっか？ / まぁ、いいですけど。
Shall we compare a bit? / Well, fine then.
ほらね。 / 待って！
See? / Wait!
吾輩のアホ毛のかげんね... / これメルのアホ毛があるからメルの勝ちだね！
With my ahoge... / Since Mel has an ahoge, Mel wins!
メルの勝ちだ！ メルの勝ちー！ / メルの勝ちー？
Mel wins! Mel wins! / Mel wins?
イェーイ！ やったー！ / いやいやいや...
Yay! All right! / No, no, no...
でもさ、ラプラスちゃんちっちゃいの可愛いからいいんじゃない？
But isn't it good that Laplus-chan is cute because she's small?
えー、いやいや、なんか丸め込もうとしてますよね？
Eh? No no, you're trying to win me over, aren't you?
あ！ そうだ！
Ah! That's right!
せっかくカッコいい歌歌ったんだしさ、2人でちょっとカッコいい決めポーズ取らん？ / ちょっと話聞いてなくね？
Since we sang such a cool song, why don't the two of us do a cool pose? / Are you even listening?
おー、いいっすね！ いいよいいよ！
Oh, sounds good! Sure, sure!
行くぞ人間たち！ ばっちりスクショ撮るのだぞー！ / 撮るのだぞー！
Here we go, humans! Take plenty of screenshots! / Take them!
よーし、じゃあまず... うん、そうだな。
Alright, first... yeah, let me see.
片手を... 手をパーにして、そうそうそう、突き出す感じ。 / はい、パー。
Put one hand... open into a palm, yeah, like pushing it out. / Okay, open palm.
おー、いいじゃないですか！ 必殺技みたいで。
Oh, isn't this cool? Like a special move!
はっ！ カッコよくない？
Ha! Doesn't it look cool?
いいんじゃない？ / 我輩に任せよ！
Looks good, right? / Leave it to me!
いいじゃん！ / お、ラプメル！
Nice! / Oh, Lap-Mel!
いいね！ / おー、いいっすねー。
Awesome! / Oh, looks good!
スッギ... いいわ！
Awes... great!
じゃあ次は腕組みして...
Okay, next, let me cross our arms...
背中合わせで...
Back to back...
うわ、いいね！ 少年漫画の王道...
Whoa, nice! Classic shonen manga...
めっちゃ近い！ / 痛っ！ すみませんすみません！
You're super close! / Ouch! Sorry, sorry!
邪魔！ 角邪魔！ メル映ってない！ / 待って待って！
In the way! Horns in the way! Mel isn't in frame! / Wait, wait!
メルさんちょっと服がエロいんで... / 被ってる被ってる！
Mel-san, your outfit is a bit erotic... / You're blocking me!
BAN対象にならないようにね！ / 気をつけないと...
So you don't get BANned! / Gotta be careful...
吾輩の気遣いね、これ！ ほら！ / あ！
This is my thoughtfulness, look! / Ah!
はぁ！？ どきなさいから！ / いや、なんでなんでなんで？
Huh?! Move out of the way! / Wait, why, why, why?
この角... いいから！ 邪魔！ どきなー！ / 痛っ！ やめて！ メルさんちょっと！
These horns... move them! Get out of the way! / Ouch! Stop! Mel-san, wait!
こちら、幸福安心委員会です。
[Title: This is the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee.]
どうして みんなが 幸せなの？
Why is everyone so happy?
この世界のこと
About this world,
聞きいたいって 知りたいって
wanting to ask, wanting to know.
水辺の公園で
In the park by the water,
みんなが 耳を澄ませて
everyone listens intently.
わくわくするね
It's so exciting,
ねぇ、オンディーヌ？
isn't it, Ondine?
ハイハーイ！
Hi hi!
さあさあ、みなさん 教えはあげまーす！
Now, now, everyone, I'll tell you!
みんなが気になっていること
What everyone is wondering about,
疑問に思っていること
what you find questionable,
ぜーんぶ教えてあげまーす！
I'll tell you absolutely everything!
えー、みなさんが幸福なのは…
Um, that you are happy...
義務なんですよ？
is a duty!
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's a duty!
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
我々、幸福安心委員会は
We, the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee,
みなさまの幸せを願い 支えまーす！
wish for everyone's happiness and support you!
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's a duty!
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's a duty!
ですから、安心して義務を果たすように！
So, fulfill your duty with peace of mind!
みなさまの幸せが
Everyone's happiness
我々の幸せ
is our happiness.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's a duty!
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら…
If you're not happy...
絞首 斬首 銃殺 釜茹で
Hanging, beheading, firing squad, boiling in a cauldron,
溺死 電気 火あぶり 生き埋め
drowning, electrocution, burning at the stake, live burial,
薬殺 石打ち 鋸 張り付け
lethal injection, stoning, sawing, crucifixion,
好きなのを選んでね
pick whichever you like!
ハイハーイ！
Hi hi!
さあさあ、みなさん 幸せだけが満ちてまーす！
Now, now, everyone, only happiness overflows!
不安とか不満 何ひとつないでしょう？
There is zero anxiety or dissatisfaction, right?
怖ぁい 怖ぁいよ
Scary, so scary
幸せすぎて 怖ぁいよ
It's so scary because I'm too happy
ほんとうに みんなが 幸せなの？
Is everyone really happy?
この世界の外 行きたいって
Saying they want to go outside this world,
逃げたいって
saying they want to escape.
水辺の公園で
In the park by the water,
みんなが耳を塞いで
everyone covered their ears
ビクビクしてた
and trembled in fear.
ねぇ ウンディーネ？
Hey, Undine?
ハイハイー！
Yes, yes!
さあさあ、みなさん 死にましたー！
Now, now, everyone, he has died!
オンディーヌを振った騎士は死にました！
The knight who dumped Ondine has died!
葬儀に出るなら向こうに並べ！
If you're attending the funeral, line up over there!
それ以外は幸せに暮らせー！
Everyone else, live happily!
以上 幸福なのは義務なんです
That is all! Being happy is your duty!
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is your duty.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is your duty.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, you know?
義務なんです
It is a duty.
義務ですよ？
It's your duty, you know?
義務なんです 幸福なのは義務なんです
It's a duty. Being happy is your duty.
義務なんです
It is a duty.
義務ですよー！
It's your duty!
義務なんです
It is a duty.
幸せじゃないなら
If you are not happy...
死ね
Die.
一緒に怒られて
Getting scolded together,
一緒に大きくなって
growing up together,
一緒に涙して
shedding tears together,
その分もっと笑った
and laughing even more in return.
仲良しの姉妹で 隠し事はなかった
We were close sisters with no secrets between us.
好きな人の話 いつか聞きたいかも
Maybe someday I'll want to hear about the person you like.
突然どうしたの？ うちら仲良しだけど
What's with you all of a sudden? We're close, but...
大人になるほどね 秘密増やしていいの！
As we grow older, it's okay to keep more secrets!
予想は芸能関係 爽やかな王子様？
My guess is someone in show business, a refreshing prince?
どうしよう…
What should I do...
全然違うし
He's completely different,
だけどいいの 王子様
but he's fine, my prince!
ぶりっ子して
Acting cute,
ほっぺつけて
pressing our cheeks together,
ポーズ決めて
striking a pose,
アップしよう
let's upload it!
大好きだよ
I love you!
見つめ合って
Staring at each other,
可愛いねって
saying "So cute!"
苦手なこと
Things we're bad at,
得意なこと
things we're good at,
好みだとか
or our preferences,
それぞれジャン？
aren't they different for each of us?
嫌いだよ
I hate you!
喧嘩しても
Even if we fight,
ずっと一緒だよね
we'll always be together, right?
ルルリラ
Lu-lu-li-ra
こちらの方ですが お付き合いをしてます！
I'm currently dating this person right here!
イメージ真逆でも ちゃんと仲良くしてね
Even if he's the total opposite of your image, please get along with him!
取られたくないから 少し拗ねてみたけど
I didn't want to lose you, so I pouted a little,
ほんと楽しそうで 私も嬉しくなった
but seeing you so happy made me happy too.
気になる人とかいないの？ お姉ちゃんに教えて
Isn't there anyone you like? Tell your big sister!
決めたの 恋愛は禁止
I've decided romance is off-limits!
今はダメ 夢のため
Not right now, for the sake of my dream!
キメ顔して
Strike a cool pose,
変顔して
make a funny face,
泣き笑いも
tears and laughter too,
アップしよう
let's upload it!
大好きだよ
I love you!
見つめ合って
Staring at each other,
可愛いねって
saying "So cute!"
似ているとか
Whether we look alike,
似てないとか
or we don't,
趣味だってさ
or even our hobbies,
それぞれジャン？
aren't they different for each of us?
嫌いだよ
I hate you!
仲直りも
Making up, too,
きっとすぐできる
I'm sure we can do it right away!
ルルリラ
Lu-lu-li-ra
一つ屋根の下で
Under one roof,
明日も騒ごう
let's make a racket tomorrow too!
ぶりっ子して
Act like a cutesy girl
ほっぺつけて
Press our cheeks together
ポーズ決めて
Strike a pose
アップしよう
Let's upload it
大好きだよ
I love you
見つめ合って
Look into each other's eyes
可愛いね
So cute
苦手なこと 得意なこと
Things we're bad at, things we're good at,
好みだとか それぞれジャン？
our preferences—everyone's different, right?
嫌いだよ
I hate you
喧嘩しても
Even if we fight,
ずっと一緒だよね
we'll always be together, right?
ルルリラ
Lululila
イェーイ！
Yaaay!
メル先輩、ハッピーバースデー！
Mel-senpai, happy birthday!
あ、アメリア！サンキュー！サンキュー、サンキュー！
Ah, Amelia! Thank you! Thank you, thank you!
一緒に歌って踊れて楽しかったよ！
Singing and dancing together was so much fun!
うん、メルも！
Yeah, me too!
あのね、今日はさ、メルの誕生日だから、何かご褒美ちょうだい！プリーズ！
You know, today is Mel's birthday, so please give me a reward!
え？何がいいかな？
Huh? What would be good?
あー、じゃあ… プリーズ、キス・ミー！
Ah, then... please kiss me!
わー！メル先輩！
Wow, Mel-senpai!
大好きー！
I love you!
Wow, me too! I love Amelia!
嬉しー！
I'm so happy!
これからも一緒に遊んでください！
Please keep hanging out with me from now on too!
Of course, Amelia!
Ah, I wanted to do something with you.
アメリアとやりたいことがある！
There's something I want to do with Amelia!
何々？
What is it?
えっとね、3rd fesで踊ってたダンスが可愛かったから、一緒にやりたい！
Um, the dance you did at 3rd Fes was so cute, so I want to do it together!
おー！
Oh!
いい？
Can we?
いいよ！
Sure!
プルプル？プルプル？
Puru-puru? Puru-puru?
わー！
Wow!
せーの！
Ready, go!
プルプル！
Puru-puru!
プルプルプルプル！
Puru-puru-puru-puru!
プルプル！
Puru-puru!
イェーイ！
Yaaay!
ダンス可愛かったよー！
That dance was so cute!
ありがとう！Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
Everyone, take lots of pictures, okay?
いっぱい撮った？写真撮った？
Did you take a lot? Did you take photos?
ちょっとアメリア近くに…
Amelia, come closer...
うん、カムカム！
Yeah, come, come!
ぎゅー！チーズ！
Hug! Cheese!
Cute! Cute! Cute!
We are cute!
メル先輩、本当に可愛い！めっちゃ可愛い！
Mel-senpai is really cute! Super cute!
アメリアも可愛いよ！
Amelia is cute too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Nice sister!
Oh, nice sister!
また遊ぼうね！
Let's play again!
メル先輩、これからもよろしくね！
Mel-senpai, let's keep getting along!
よろしくね！
Likewise!
また遊びましょう！
Let's hang out again!
遊びましょう！これからもアメルをよろしくー！
Let's hang out! Please support Ameru in the future too!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
どうもこんにちは君の分身です
"Hello there, I'm your alter ego."
何の冗談か目を擦ってみる
Thinking it's a joke, I rub my eyes.
影が二つ伸びて
Two shadows stretch out,
そしてまた幕が上がる
and once again, the curtain rises.
もう一人自分がいたらとあなたは言いました
"If only there were another me," you said.
そんな真摯な願いが僕を呼んだのさ
Such an earnest wish is what summoned me.
そりゃ願ったりだ！この難題 苦痛 惨難 全ての代行者
That's a dream come true! A stand-in for all your problems, pain, and disasters.
過程はいいから結果を下さい
Forget the process, just give me results.
無意味で無意義な代償
A meaningless, senseless compensation.
ねぇこんな事より大事な事があるんだ
Hey, there's something more important than this.
良いだろう
"Alright then."
ええやりますやります何でもやりまーす
"Yeah, I'll do it, I'll do anything!"
僕は君の分身ですし
"After all, I'm your alter ego."
含み笑いで救世主は言う
With a smirk, the savior speaks.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君の誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you to yourself?
嗚呼 混濁と交差して 僕は誰？
Ah, crossing through the chaos, who am I?
ねぇ 有りもしない＃0と
Hey, with the non-existent #0
証明の根拠なんて何処にも
and no proof of existence anywhere.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は彼の君
Dear Doppelganger, who is that person?
蝕まれた存在に 世界は気付かないね
The world doesn't notice a corrupted existence, does it?
鳴り止まない 覚めない 奇跡の輪廻が
The endless, unawakening cycle of miracles
狂った正解を染め上げて
paints over the twisted correct answer,
ルンパッパ
Lumpappa!
どうも調子がおかしい月曜日
Somehow, I feel off on this Monday.
一つ二つ食い違っていく通義が
One by one, common logic begins to clash,
僕を定義する
defining who I am.
ちょっと待って 知らない昨日
Wait a second, a yesterday I don't know,
知りもしない言葉
and words I don't even know.
そうやっていつの間にやら 影は溶けゆく
Just like that, before I knew it, my shadow fades away.
僕は何なんだろう ねぇ
What on earth am I? Hey,
どうか存在を返して
please give me back my existence!
「生憎様だがこっちはこっちで 随分心地が良くて」
"Unfortunate for you, but over here, it's quite comfortable,"
「もうあなたの居場所は 此処にはない事分かってるんでしょ」
"you already know there's no place for you here anymore, right?"
「ねえ 奪われたんなら奪えばいいだろ 今度はお前の番だから」
"Hey, if it was stolen, why not steal it back? It's your turn now."
含み笑いで 侵略者は謳う
With a smirk, the invader sings.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰
Dear Doppelganger, who, who are you?
嗚呼 混濁と交差して 僕は誰
Ah, crossing with confusion, who am I?
そうさ 昨日の影すらもう居やしないな 命の椅子は一つだけ
That's right, even yesterday's shadow is gone now. There's only one chair of life.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は 誰は君
Dear Doppelganger, who, who are you?
零れ落ちた一粒 乾き果てる前に
Before that single spilled drop completely dries up,
誰でもいい 何でもいい 器を下さい
anyone is fine, anything is fine, please give me a vessel!
狂った正解が 染め上げてるんだ
A twisted correctness is painting over everything.
それはずっと続く ヒトの業の連鎖
It continues forever, a chain of human karma.
委ね合って 許し合って 満たされ往く
Entrusting each other, forgiving each other, becoming fulfilled.
欠けたピース 無価値のペイン 冀望また愛も
Missing pieces, worthless pain, hope and love too.
託し合って 生まれ変わる イニシエイション
Entrusting to each other, reborn through initiation.
「僕のほうがちゃんと 君を生きてやるから」
"Because I'll live you out properly,"
「君も次の誰か ちゃんと救わなくちゃ」
"you must properly save the next person, too."
もう分かってんのなら 何をすればいいかさ
If you already know, then you know what to do...
「どうか誰か僕に奇跡をくれよ」
"Please, someone give me a miracle!"
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰
Dear Doppelganger, who, who are you?
嗚呼 混濁と交差して 僕は誰
Ah, crossing with confusion, who am I?
もう止まらない もう戻れない
It won't stop, can't go back,
そう思わないかい？ こんにちは君の
don't you think so? Hello, I'm your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それは それは僕
Dear Doppelganger, that is, that is me.
奪い取られた存在に
To the existence that was stolen,
正解が幾つあろうが 止まらない溜息
no matter how many right answers there are, unceasing sighs...
奇跡の輪廻が 狂った正解を
The cycle of miracles, a twisted correctness...
染め上げるさ 幕開けだよ
will paint over it. The curtain is rising!
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
"Well hello, I am your alter ego."
どうだっていいことを 嘘って吐いて戻れない
Spewing lies about things that don't matter, I can't go back.
時効なんてやってこない 奪ったように奪われて
A statute of limitations will never come; just as I stole, I am stolen from.
今日だって叶わない 思ったように騙せない
Even today it doesn't come true, I can't deceive like I thought.
腐っている僕には 腐ったものが分からない
To a rotten me, I can't even tell what's rotten.
おいでココまで 手え叩いて
Come here, clap your hands!
「隠して仕舞ったんだ」
"I ended up hiding it away."
メーデー 僕と判っても
Mayday! Even if you recognize me,
もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
you don't have to hold me tight anymore.
メーデー 僕が解ったら
Mayday! If you figure me out,
もう笑わなくていいんだよ
you don't have to smile anymore.
ねえ 僕が分かっても
Hey, even if you understand me,
もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
you don't have to hold me tight anymore.
ねえ 僕が解ったら
Hey, if you figure me out,
もう一度笑ってくれるかな
will you smile for me once again?
マボロシだって知るんだよ
I know it's just an illusion!
嘘つきだって知るんだよ ねぇ
I know I'm a liar! Hey...
どうだっていいはずが
Even though it was supposed to not matter,
気取ってYESと言い出す
I put on airs and say "YES".
後悔の静寂は
The silence of regret...
騙したほうが正義なの？
Is deceiving someone actually justice?
卑怯だって構わない
I don't care if it's cowardly,
気取っておいてそれはない
putting on airs and then doing that, no way.
飾っていた長舌が
The long-winded speech I was dressing up,
墓穴を掘って消える様
digging its own grave and disappearing...
おいでおいで
Come here, come here...
被害者面したって
Even if I act like the victim,
ねえ 僕を持ち去ってよ
Hey, take me away!
常識外の愛 ゆめ見たなら
If you dreamed of an unconventional love,
手前で僕を裁いてよ
then judge me with your own hands.
最後まで甘え尽くしてしまうのは
Relying completely on you until the very end...
亡霊だって知るんだよ
I know it's because I'm a ghost!
空白だって知るんだよ ねぇ
I know it's because I'm a blank space! Hey...
足りないものを望んだら
If I desired what's missing...
出会ったよ
We met,
それのまま前に進んだの
and moved forward just like that,
グラグラしちゃうよ
I feel all dizzy.
誰も僕を愛しては
No one loves me,
エゴママが僕を刺したの
selfishness stabbed me.
君には僕が見えるかな
Can you see me?
孤独なピエロが
A lonely clown...
メーデー 僕と分かっても もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
Mayday, even if you know it's me, you don't need to hold me close anymore.
メーデー 僕が解ったら もう一度笑ってくれるかな
Mayday, if you understand me, will you smile for me once more?
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ 正直者が夢見たんなら
Mayday, scold me; if an honest person were to dream...
メーデー 僕を裁いてよ 最後まで甘えてしまうのは
Mayday, judge me; to be spoiled until the very end...
メーデー 僕を暴いてよ もうすぐ終わるこの世界から
Mayday, expose me, from this world that is soon ending.
メーデー 僕と踊ってよ 最初からいないと分かってた
Mayday, dance with me; I knew from the start I wasn't here.
Say wow!
幻だって知るんだよ
I know I'm just an illusion!
Say wow!
嘘つきだって知るんだよ
I know I'm just a liar!
Say wow!
亡霊だって知るんだよ
I know I'm just a ghost!
Say wow!
遠ざかっていったんだよ
Fading further and further away!
どうだっていいことを
About things that don't even matter,
嘘って吐いて戻れない
I spewed lies and can't turn back.
時効なんてやってこない
No statute of limitations will ever come,
奪ったように奪われて
robbed just as I have robbed.
メル先輩！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Mel-senpai! Happy birthday!
わー！ありがとう、こよちゃん！
Yay! Thank you, Koyo-chan!
いや、本当に一緒に歌えて嬉しいです！呼んでいただき...
I'm so happy we could sing together! Thanks for inviting me...
嬉しい！あー、ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy! Ah, thank you so much!
なんですが、ちょっと... こより、メル先輩にこの機会にちょっと聞きたいことがあるんですが...
However, um... there's something Koyori wanted to ask Mel-senpai while I have the chance...
なに？
What is it?
あの、なんかこよりとは「ワンナイト」とか「ツーナイト」とか言ってたじゃないですか？
Um, didn't you say things like "one night" or "two nights" with Koyori?
あーね、言ったね、そのこと。
Ah, right, I did say that.
そこんところどうなんですか？結局こよりのこと、どう思ってるんですか？
What's the deal with that? In the end, what do you really think of Koyori?
え？あー... いや、こより...
Huh? Ah... well, Koyori...
何言ってるんだ。もう初めてのお風呂も、その他諸々も...
What are you talking about? Our first bath together, and various other things...
こよりが初めてなんだぜ。
...Koyori was my first for all of them.
もうそれって、どういう意味か... 分かるよな？
You understand... what that means, right?
急にイケボ... 惚れたー！
Suddenly a deep cool voice... I fell for you!
ダー！
Bam!
よし！
Alright!
なんか声が聞こえた気がするけどな、今、心の声が。
I feel like I heard a voice just now... the voice of your heart.
こよちゃん、そうだ、そうだ。せっかく3Dコラボなんだから、一緒に何か写真撮ろうよ。
Koyo-chan, that's right! Since we're doing a 3D collab, let's take a picture together!
あ、はい！撮ります！流された気がするけど... はい！
Ah, yes! Let me take one! I feel like I got brushed off, but... okay!
やったー！
Yay!
何撮ろうかな？
What pose should we do?
どうしましょうか？
What should we do?
じゃあ、名探偵メルこよだから、我らね。
Well, since we're Great Detectives Mel & Koyo...
はいはい。
Right, right.
なんかそれっぽいポーズとらん？
Shall we do a pose that fits that?
あ、いいですね！
Ah, sounds good!
そしたら、じゃああれかな... あれだね！
In that case, maybe that pose... Yeah, that one!
背中合わせにして...
Let me stand back-to-back...
かっこよく決めよう！
And strike a cool pose!
オーケーです！
Okay!
行くよ？
Ready?
はい！
Yes!
せーの！真実は、いつも、ひとつ！
One, two... The truth is always one!
あ、かっこいい！かっこいい！
Ah, so cool! So cool!
決まったんじゃない？みんなパシャパシャ撮ってね。
Didn't we nail it? Everyone, snap lots of photos, okay?
撮ってください！
Please take photos!
いいねいいね！これは謎が解けるぞ！
Nice, nice! This will solve any mystery!
名探偵の「名」も迷うじゃなくて「名」になりそうですね。
It feels like the "Mei" in Great Detective will actually mean "great" instead of "lost"!
そうだそうだ！
That's right, that's right!
じゃあ次さ...
Then next...
あの、いいですか？可愛いポーズとか...
Um, is it okay? A cute pose...
何何？
What, what?
可愛いで、ちょっとね、ちゃんとこよりとはワンナイトとか言わせないために、ぎゅーって感じの...
A cute one, so that people won't say it's just a "one night" thing with Koyori anymore, like a tight hug...
ぎゅーって感じの？
A tight hug kind of pose?
証拠写真撮らせてもらっていいですか？
Can we take a photo as proof?
ぎゅーってして... やったー！
Holding tight... Yay!
恥ずかしい... 恥ずかしい...
I'm embarrassed... so embarrassed...
ドキドキが伝わってくる気がする！
I feel like I can feel your heart pounding!
初めてだよ、こよちゃんと。
It's my first time doing this, with Koyo-chan.
撮られている、みんなに... おお、全員に見られて撮られている...
Everyone is taking photos of us... Whoa, everyone is watching and taking pictures...
何考えてんの、もう！
What are you thinking, jeez!
うー、何でもないです！何でもないです！
Uuu, it's nothing! It's nothing!
こよちゃん、今日は本当にありがとう！一緒に歌えてメルもめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったよ！
Koyo-chan, thank you so much for today! Mel was super happy to sing together with you!
こよりの方こそです！
Likewise, from Koyori!
これからも、らぶらぶしていきましょうね！
Let's keep being all lovey-dovey from now on too, okay?
していこうね！
Let's do that!
こんこよー！ こんこゆー！
Konkoyo~! Konkoyu~!
[曲名：HANAJI]
[Song: HANAJI]
ドッキリ ドッキリ 興奮しちゃう
Heart pounding, heart pounding, getting excited!
じっと手を見る ドキッとしちゃう ハートはハイテンション
Staring at my hands, my heart skips a beat, high tension!
運命の恋を探しに来たけど 目移り 腕まくり
I came looking for the love of my life, but my eyes wander and I roll up my sleeves.
ビシッとバシッと決めたいけれど 難解 展開 幸せ咲きまくり
I want to make a bold move, but it's complex with twists and turns, happiness in full bloom!
誰かと秘密を分け合う奴に 押され気味ですの
I'm feeling a bit overwhelmed by someone sharing a secret.
愛するに余りある カミングアウト 責められ いじられ やめてやめて あーあー
Coming out with more love than I can handle! Blamed, teased, stop it, stop it, ah-ah!
追い詰められて 振り回されて 飴と無知のムチで 破裂しそう
Cornered and jerked around, about to burst from sweet candy and ignorant whips!
ど直球でイカれちゃうくらい いじられちゃう だけど快感なの
Teased so directly it drives me crazy, but it feels so good!
ドッキリ ドッキリ ホッとしたり ズッキン ドッキン ワクワク
Heart pounding, heart pounding, feeling relieved, throbbing, fluttering, excited!
じっと手を見る ドキッとしちゃう ハートはハイテンション
Staring at my hands, my heart skips a beat, high tension!
ソワソワ モドモド 絶好調だね 期待も浮きまくり
Restless and fidgety, in peak condition, expectations soaring!
タフにチャージ 無視決め込む 妄想にされても ノリまくり
Toughly charging up, ignoring it all, even if turned into a delusion, going all out!
勘違いじゃないの 心のヒダで 本当は静かに
It's no mistake, deep within the folds of my heart, truly quiet...
ピンプ ピンプ アウト カミングアウト ディープに ディープに 埋もれたいの あーあー
Pimp, pimp out, coming out, wanting to be buried deep, deep down, ah-ah!
巡り巡り巡りてベイビー 今は耐えて 伏せて 妄想の過剰なの
Going round and round, baby! Now enduring, lying low, overloaded with delusions!
ど直球でたぶらかされても 罵られても だけど虜になっちゃう
Even if deceived so directly or insulted, I still become captive to it!
誰かと秘密を分け合う奴に 押され気味ですの
I'm feeling a bit overwhelmed by someone sharing a secret.
愛するに余りある カミングアウト 責められ いじられ やめてやめて あーあー
Coming out with more love than I can handle! Blamed, teased, stop it, stop it, ah-ah!
追い詰められて 振り回されて 飴と無知のムチで 破裂しそう
Cornered and jerked around, about to burst from sweet candy and ignorant whips!
ど直球でイカれちゃうくらい いじられちゃう だけど快感なの
Teased so directly it drives me crazy, but it feels so good!
ドッキリ ドッキリ ホッとしたり ズッキン ドッキン ワクワク
Heart pounding, heart pounding, feeling relieved, throbbing, fluttering, excited!
じっと手を見る ドキッとしちゃう ハートはハイテンション
Staring at my hands, my heart skips a beat, high tension!
はーい！というわけで、メルちゃん！
Alright! So, Mel-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう！ / ありがとう！
Happy birthday! / Thank you!
あ、ちょうどさ、去年の誕生日ライブにもマリン来てくれたよね？
Ah, Marine came to my birthday live stream last year too, right?
そうだよ！
That's right!
メルちゃんさ、え、もしかして…マリンのこと好き？
Mel-chan, wait... could it be that you like Marine?
え？ひ、引いてないよ！
Eh? I-I'm not drawing back!
で、でもさ、メルね、マリンともっと遊びたいなーって思ってるよ？
B-But, you know, Mel wants to hang out with Marine more!
ほう！
Oh?
人間界にも最近来たばかりだし、今度はさ、うちに来ないか？マリン。
I only came to the human world recently, so why don't you visit my place next time, Marine?
め、メルちゃんちに！？え、一体何にされちゃうのー！？
T-To Mel-chan's place?! What are you gonna do to me?!
え？この間の続きに決まってるでしょ？
Huh? Continuing where we left off the other day, of course!
な、なんすか続き？この間とかちょっと過去すぎて忘れたんだけど…何だっけ？
W-What do you mean, where we left off? That was so long ago I forgot... What was it?
ふふ、だからさっさと来てネタ出すんだよ！
Hehe, so hurry up and come over so we can brainstorm!
ええ！？さそ…誘っといて…メルちゃん自意識過剰だな！別に誘ってないんだけど！
Eh?! Inv-Inviting me... Mel-chan, you're so full of yourself! I didn't ask to be invited!
誘ってたよ！チャット来たよすぐに！秒で出たじゃん！
You did! You texted me right away! In a split second!
おー…ま、まあちょっと…ちょっと忘れたけど、今度ね、メルちゃんち行こうかな！
Oh... W-Well... I forgot a bit, but maybe I'll visit your place next time, Mel-chan!
やったー！決まりね！
Yay! It's a deal!
マジでマリンのこと好きだなー、困ったなー。
You really love Marine, don't you? What am I going to do with you?
はいはいはいはい！じゃあ…
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah! Well then...
マリンせっかく1年越しにね、2人で3Dライブだから、なんかポーズ一緒に撮ろ？
Marine, since we're doing a 3D live together after a whole year, let's take a pose together!
あ、いいよいいよー！え、どんなポーズにする？
Ah, sure, sure! What kind of pose should we do?
そうだなー、さっきの曲中だと、なんか…
Let's see... From that song earlier, maybe...
白猫メルで黒猫マリンだったから
Since it was White Cat Mel and Black Cat Marine...
あー確かに
Ah, true.
ちょっと逆のも見たいかなー
I kind of want to see the opposite too~
マリン攻め？
Marine taking the lead?
うん
Yeah.
ちょっとスーパーダーリン見せるか...いやでもさ
Should I show off my Super Darling side... wait, but
SM系の方がいいのかな
Is SM style better?
精一杯のマリンのイジメを見たいかな
I kind of want to see Marine bully me with all her might.
あーなるほど、じゃあちょっと...
Ah, I see. Then let me...
メルちゃん、ちょっと歯食い縛ってもらっても...
Mel-chan, could you clench your teeth for a second...
いいかな？
Is it okay?
バシーン！
Slap!
メル！この豚！この豚！
Mel! You pig! You pig!
メル、ほら膝まずきなさい！
Mel, come on, get on your knees!
膝まずき！
Get on my knees!
あら、痛い！
Oh, it hurts!
これぞ！
This is it!
好きです！
I love it!
気持ちいいです！
It feels so good!
あ、やっぱり好きなんだ。これ気持ちいいのね！
Ah, so you really like it. This feels good, huh!
うふーい！
Woohoo!
こんな変態とはお友達でいられませーん！
I can't be friends with such a pervert!
お前も変態だろうが！
You're a pervert too!
バレちゃったなー
You caught me~
ちょっとドロッとしてきた...汚い空気になってきたから...
It's getting a bit murky... the atmosphere got dirty...
ポーズ取ろうか！ね！
Let's strike a pose! Right!
最後はちょっと可愛く決めようか！
Let's strike a cute pose at the end!
2人愛し合ってるってことが完全に判明したから...
Since it's totally clear we love each other...
ハート作ろっか！
Shall we make a heart?
うん、2人でハート！
Yup, a heart for two!
はい、それでは！はい、せーのっ！
Alright then! Ready, set...
イエーイ！
Yay!
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
そういう扱い 心得てよね
So make sure you know by heart how to treat me, got it?
イェーイ！ いいね？
Yay! Do I make myself clear?
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気がつくこと
First thing, notice when I have a different hair style from usual
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね？
Second thing, be sure to go as far as looking down at my shoes properly, do I make myself clear?
その三 わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Third thing, for every single word I say, reply with three words
わかったら右手がお留守なのなんとかして！
If you understand that there is nothing in my right hand, then do something!
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
I'm not really saying anything selfish
キミに心から思ってほしいの かわいいって
I want you to think from your heart that I'm cute
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
気がついて ねぇねぇ 待たせるなんて論外よ
Realize that, hey, hey, keeping me waiting is out of the question
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだかあまいものが食べたい！
Somehow I would already like to eat something sweet!
いますぐによ
Go get it immediately
チェックワンツー！
Check one-two!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ 文句は許しませんの
My fault? Let's call it a cute mistake, complaints are not permitted
あのね？わたしの話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっとー
Well? Are you clearly hearing what I am saying? Come on
あ、それね 白いお馬さん決まってるでしょ？
Ah, and what about this? A white horse, isn't that needless to say?
迎えに来て
Come and take me away
わかったらかしずいて手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand that, take my hand and say "princess"
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
I'm not really saying anything selfish
でもね 少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
But you know, it's alright to scold me a little?
世界でわたしだけのおうじさま
My very own prince in the world
気がついて ほらほら おててがあいてます
Realize that, look, look, our hands are empty
無口でぶあいそうなおうじさま
Reticent and blunt prince
もうどうして！気をつけろよ 早く
Come on, why! Just notice it soon
絶対キミはわかってない！わかってないわ...
You definitely don't understand! Don't understand...
いちごののったショートケーキ こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
Shortcake with a strawberry on top, pudding made with well-selected eggs
みんなみんな我慢します...
Everything, everything, I will hold myself back from it
わがままな子だと思わないで
Don't think that I'm a selfish girl
私だってやればできるもん 後で後悔するわよ
Even I will be able to do it if I try, you will regret this afterwards
当然です！だって私は
It's natural! Even for me
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ？
See me clearly okay, shall I go somewhere?
ふいに抱きしめられた 急にそんな え？
Suddenly I was held tightly, it was so abrupt, eh?
「ひかれる あぶないよ」
"It's dangerous, you'll get hit,"
そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
so saying, you turn your head away.
…こっちのがあぶないわよ
...This side is much more dangerous, you know!
みんなー！
Everyone~!
こんかっぷー！
Konkappu~!
ライブ楽しんでるー？
Are you enjoying the live stream?
メルっとっとね、めちゃくちゃ楽しんでるよメルは！
Mel is enjoying it so much!
今年のハロウィンも誕生日も
This year's Halloween and my birthday...
みんなのおかげで、めっちゃ楽しい！ありがとうー！
...are super fun thanks to everyone! Thank you~!
でね、今回のステージ、もう気づいてくれたかなー？
And you know, have you noticed this stage yet?
今回もね、メル仕様になんと作っていただきましたー！
This time as well, it was custom-made for Mel!
ドドーン！
Ta-da!
可愛いでしょー？
Isn't it cute?
すごいですよー！
It's amazing!
ねー、めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
Right? It's so cute!
今日はね、いつもよりもすごい告知があります！
Today, I have an even bigger announcement than usual!
それはこのあと説明するので、ぜひ最後まで聞いてってください！
I'll explain it after this, so please listen until the end!
まずは！
First of all!
デデデデーン！夜空メル 誕生日記念グッズ2022！
Ta-da! Yozora Mel Birthday Commemorative Goods 2022!
ドドドドーン！
Ta-da-da-da!
今回も可愛いグッズをいっぱい用意してます！
We've prepared lots of cute goods this time too!
その1！
Number 1!
夜空メル バースデーライト 〜LEDアクリルスタンドライト〜
Yozora Mel Birthday Light ~LED Acrylic Stand Light~!
浅ぎゆな先生描き下ろしのイラストだよ！
It features a newly drawn illustration by Asagi Yuna-sensei!
かっこいいでしょ？
It's cool, isn't it?
いつも可愛いメルだけど、今回はかっこ可愛いメルに描いていただきました！
Usually I'm a cute Mel, but this time she drew a cool-and-cute Mel!
お部屋でね、ぜひ使ってください！
Please use it in your room!
そしてその2！
And number 2!
魔界の晩餐会グラス！
Demon Realm Banquet Glass!
これワイングラスです！
This is a wine glass!
これね、メルずっと作りたかったんだよね！
You know, Mel has always wanted to make this!
メルはアセロラジュースを入れてね、飲むつもりだけど
Mel plans to fill it with acerola juice and drink it, but...
みんなはワインとか、ぶどうジュースとか入れてね、ぜひ美味しく飲んでください！
everyone can pour wine or grape juice in it and enjoy drinking it!
いっぱい使ってね！
Please use it a lot!
その3！
Number 3!
メルの魔導書パスケース！
Mel's Grimoire Pass Case!
これパスケースになってます！
This is a pass case!
日常でぜひいっぱい使ってほしいな！
I hope you use it a lot in your daily life!
実はね、この本のスガラ...
Actually, the pattern on this book...
今後メルの配信や歌ってみたなどで出てくる予定があります！
is planned to appear in Mel's future streams, cover songs, and more!
何処でかはちょっと今ナイショなんだけど...
Where and how is a secret for now, but...
その時のお楽しみということで
look forward to seeing it then,
皆さんぜひ先取りでゲットしてほしいな！
and I hope everyone gets it in advance!
そして！次がビッグなお知らせ！
And next is a huge announcement!
その4！
Number 4!
デデデデーン！夜空メル 1st Album 『Twinkle Star Magic★』！
Ta-da! Yozora Mel 1st Album "Twinkle Star Magic★"!
これはぜひゲットしてほしい、一番ゲットしてほしいやつ！
I really want you to get this, it's the item I want you to get the most!
かっこいい曲からね、可愛い曲、しっとり曲などなどいっぱい詰め込みました！
From cool songs to cute songs, solemn songs and more, it's packed with so much!
いろんなメルを知ってほしいなと思ってたくさん詰め込んだので、ぜひ聴いてほしいです！
I wanted you to get to know various sides of Mel, so I packed a lot into it, please listen to it!
全部でなんと…ドゥルル… 11曲あります！
In total, there are... *drumroll*... 11 songs!
メルね、5ヶ月連続でオリ曲リリースしてたんですけど
Mel released original songs for 5 consecutive months,
『Capu Chino』から今までのオリ曲、そしてね
from "Capu Chino" to my previous original songs, and also...
まだ配信されてない曲がなんと5曲も入って
there are 5 songs that haven't been released digitally yet,
合計11曲になってます！
making a total of 11 songs!
さらに！メルの初めてのオリ曲『Capu Chino』のリミックスバージョンも入っています！
Furthermore! A remix version of Mel's first original song, "Capu Chino," is also included!
さらにさらに！
And even more!
『Daily Diary』の夜空メル歌唱バージョンも入ってます！
The Yozora Mel vocal version of "Daily Diary" is included too!
これね、メル1人で5役演じて歌いました！
For this, Mel sang while acting out 5 different roles all by myself!
めちゃ頑張ったから聴いてください！
I worked super hard on it, so please listen to it!
お姉さんボイスとか少年ボイスとかね、そんな感じで歌ったので聴いてください！よろしくお願いします！
I sang with voices like big sister voice, young boy voice, and so on, so please listen! Thank you!
今回ね、グッズ全部買ってくれた人には今回も特典があります！
This time, for those who buy the full set of goods, there are special bonuses as well!
1つ目は、メルからのラブレターです！
First is a love letter from Mel!
これ初めてかもしれないね！
This might be the first time!
その2！ASMRボイス！
Number 2! ASMR voice!
こっちもね、甘々になってるので、合わせて、全部合わせてね、聴いてみてください！
This one is also super sweet, so please listen to everything together!
ぜひぜひ… めっちゃ噛んだわ！
Please be sure to... I stumbled over my words so much!
もう歌いまくってさ、息が…
I've been singing so much, my breath...
いっぱいぜひゲットしてください！
Please be sure to get the full set!
ちょっと告知長くなっちゃったけど
My announcement ran a bit long, but...
今日はこのあと、メンバー限定でアフターライブやります！
today after this, we'll have an after-live stream exclusively for members!
もっと
More,
もっと 一緒に
more, together...
もうちょっとだけ 一緒にいたいなと思って
I thought, "I want to stay together just a little longer,"
予定作ったんだけど メルと一緒にいてくれますか？
so I made time. Will you stay with Mel?
やったー！
Yay!
約束だよ！
It's a promise!
じゃあ 次が最後の曲になります
Well then, the next song will be the last one.
きっともう かぷ民のみんななら 合いの手ね バッチリだよね？ 大丈夫だよね？
I'm sure all of Kapu-min already have the call-and-responses down, right? You're good, right?
知らないよって人いたら まあこの後ね ダウンロードしてください！ めっちゃいい曲なので
If anyone doesn't know it, well, please download it after this! It's such a great song,
聴いてほしいです！
so I want you to listen to it!
今日もね 本当に本当にありがとう
Thank you so, so much for today, too,
かぷ民のみんな！
everyone in Kapu-min!
大好きだよ！ かーぷ！
I love you all! Ka-pu!
じゃあメル こっちで歌っちゃおう！
Well then, Mel is going to sing over here!
かぷうぃん中毒
[Title: Kapuine Chuudoku]
星の数より 歳の数だけ それは節分
Rather than stars, count your age... wait, that's Setsubun!
お菓子をちょーだい
Give me some treats!
おばけかき分け 夜をかけてゆく
Pushing past ghosts, running through the night,
わたし ヴァンパイア
I am a vampire!
ぱっぱらパンプキンが 頬染めて
The silly pumpkins are blushing,
てってれ照れちゃって かわいいな
getting all embarrassed and cute!
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんもお年頃
Jack-o'-Lantern is at that age, too,
ドキドキしてるのわかるくらい 近づいて
so get close enough to feel his heart pounding!
Oh ハロー ハロー Win-win
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win!
かぷってしたら
If I take a bite,
Oh ハロー ハロー Win-win
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win!
るんるんるん
Run, run, run!
ハロー ハロー Win-win
Hello, hello! Win-win!
そんなカンケイ
That kind of relationship!
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん かぷうぃん
Kapuine, Kapuine, Kapuine!
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん With you
Kapuine, Kapuine with you!
魔女 フランケン 悪魔 ミイラ ゾンビ
Witches, Frankensteins, devils, mummies, zombies!
逢魔が時の大物ぞろい
All the big shots assemble at twilight!
Ah 全員注目 その眼釘付け
Ah, all eyes on me, eyes glued to the stage!
ワクワクしてるよ いざ Party Night
Excited and ready, here comes Party Night!
お耳かぷかぷ おなかたぷたぷ
Nibbling on ears, tummy's so full,
あなた成分 たくさんちょーだい
give me plenty of your essence!
気配嗅ぎ分け 夜をかけてゆく
Sniffing out your presence, running through the night,
わたし ヴァンパイア
I am a vampire!
Oh ハロー ハロー Win-win
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win!
かぷってしたら
If I take a bite,
Oh ハロー ハロー Win-win
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win!
るんるんるん
Run, run, run!
ハロー ハロー Win-win
Hello, hello! Win-win!
そんなカンケイ
That kind of relationship!
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん かぷうぃん
Kapuine, Kapuine, Kapuine!
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん With you
Kapuine, Kapuine with you!
キュートが過ぎちゃって ごめんね！
Sorry for being way too cute!
ボンキュッボンでセクシーポーズ かわいい！
Curvaceous sexy pose! So cute!
あなたの心とカラダに メル！メル！
In your heart and body! Mel! Mel!
魔界の？ 天才！ 最強！ かわいい！ ヴァンパイアって～？ 夜空メル！
Demon realm's? Genius! Strongest! Cutest! Vampire is...? Yozora Mel!
ぱっぱらパンプキンはどこにいる？
Where are the silly pumpkins?
とっとと遠くまで行っちゃった？
Did they run off somewhere far away?
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんの浮気者！
Jack-o'-Lantern, you cheater!
ボコボコにしても 連れて帰る 覚悟して！
Even if I have to beat you up, I'm taking you home, so prepare yourself!
離れたくないよ
I don't want to leave you,
離さないよ
I won't let you go,
いつまでもずっと一緒がいいな
I want us to be together forever and ever!
このお祭り 共に過ごそう
Let's spend this festival together,
ハロウィン ハロウィン ハロウィン
Halloween, Halloween, Halloween!
Oh ハロー ハロー Win-win
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win!
かぷってしたら
If I take a bite,
Oh ハロー ハロー Win-win
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win!
るんるんるん
Run, run, run!
ハロー ハロー Win-win
Hello, hello! Win-win!
そんなカンケイ
That kind of relationship!
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん かぷうぃん
Kapuine, Kapuine, Kapuine!
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん With you
Kapuine, Kapuine with you!
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん 中毒
Kapuine, Kapuine Addiction!
たくさんのお祝いありがとう！！ これからもよろしくね♡ だいすきだぞっ♡
[Message: Thank you for all the birthday wishes!! Let's keep staying together ♡ I love you so much ♡]